Hello friends, welcome once
again to Insurance Guruji channel. Today we will
read about claim. The film is
called claim in Hindi. What is it? If
you want to take money from LIC, then in what ways will
you get it? There are some types of claims in
insurance. So let's know
how many types of claims you can take. How many types of
claims can you take from someone? So let's
start. The first one is survival
benefit. It is called
survivor benefit in Hindi. It means that only if the service is there,
they will be given the money. So when will they get it?
As I explained to you in Types of Claims.
Money back policy.
You are given survival benefit in it.
Whatever term you have
decided, like you want money every four years
or you
want money every 5 years, then why is LIC giving you it in 5 years or 4 years?
Because you have done it.
If you die, then
what do you get? Basically, it is
survival benefit which is
given to you after a short period of time.
It is also called survival benefit in seconds.
Maturity in Hindi is called
maturity, what will happen in it, whatever
endowment plan you have or any
plan, when there will be maturity, that is, at
whatever time you decide that you want to
take a policy of fifteen years, then you will make
payment in those twenty years and
after 2 years, what will be the payment that you will get, the
return that you will get from LIC,
I will do that
till maturity, thirdly a permanent disability benefit, we had read in our history about
Accident Death and Disability Benefit
Rider, what we saw in it that if
you get disabled due to an accident
or your hand gets fractured, then at that
time your disability is permanent due to
which it goes, during that time LIC
gives you permanent disability benefit,
later you are
given an amount to live in life and there was
premium waiver benefit as we also
mentioned in it, PWB rider, so
what will happen in it, you will get home time in PWB,
but if someone
takes PWB on behalf of children, then
What will happen during that time if it happens under Father Ahmed,
then whatever will be the amount of his death claim,
it will be
put in the children's policy, what will be the difference, the
children will not need to pay till it is 1 inch plus,
whatever their father and mother
program was, that point will be
put in the children's policy, so the full
benefit is not given to you in this,
it gets adjusted in the children's policy,
friends, as we had mentioned in the
surrender, when he wants to close the policy
and if
he wants to take some percentage of whatever we have paid, then
what will happen, he can take it by closing the policy, he will get the
surrender, what will
we do with it, the surrender value
in Hindi is called Samarpan Muraliya 6pm,
which is called death claim in Hindi,
what will happen when the life of this note is celebrated, what will be the
award given to him, it will be the
net claim and there are two types of death claim, so
we will see that in the NAC line,
types of death claim, there are
two types of hostels on this platform  I have taken a
container from Ratlam, I have seen it, I have seen it,
what will happen in the policy of Vanish and Within Three Years
having taken it, if any customer
makes a policy and within the starting 3s of the policy, if it is his
Meghnad, then this will be done, they
can go there and investigate them, if someone
dies, then first of all,
in ghee, like if it is his wife or mother, then whoever feels that he is not a relative, then
he will
give a statement that he was my relative and in
this way, he needs medical leave from
office, if there is any problem due to his medical condition, if there is a
medical from his office, then the
office needs medical leave application from the hospital, the
bank statements, all those
reports are needed,
then in the fourth, what will he want, which will be made after the
post-mortem, we also
need that, what time do we have to give it along with that,
whatever will come from his legal side,
after the policy, that too will have to be submitted,
okay, whatever percentage of KYC is there,
we will have to give it from their cell,
like Aadhar, PAN,
passport, anyone from this side  They
can submit it along with the documents, so
friend, our Ali Sheikh Saleem, now let us
see what is the normal Grand Slam dance love, one should rise after
three years
of age and if the Deccan policy is
after three years of the customer taking the policy,
then in that case it will be counted as early death
claim and this will
not be full on which date and there are very high chances
of masturbation also and in this case
also the documents will be taken, so that document is
required, nominee statement from the website
plant, this pass is required from the air, this is the
praise of our country's team,
this is very important and in this many times
in PIMS they also ask for documents required,
so you do not have to get confused between early and two,
Ali, now you
can calculate directly that what happened earlier
means it happened in 3 years from the starting, it happened early,
it will go as early claim
and what happened after 3 years will be done in the nominal
list, in Hindi we call this as early
death  Claim and No DM are called in Hindi
and early death claim now we will see
with suicide tax if a person commits suicide
and if he had an insurance policy
then what will happen in that case first of all we will
see that this year this installed committed
suicide law within 105 hours of the policy if
these stars have committed suicide within one year of taking the policy i.e.
in the starting one
year then
what will happen no that for that they will not be given the bill paid, yes
friends
if a customer commits suicide in the first year of this policy
then they will not be given the bill paid,
but what is the second in this dynasty
and committed suicide after one year of foreign
trade policy, the
net claim will be paid if the
customer commits suicide after one year of taking the policy
then in that case they will be taken back but
here the same thing will come, early death lemon
ODM so here it will be in which cases
friend Ali Replay and it will be done
in restaurant so friends these were our
today's topics I hope you will
not have any doubt in this if you  If there is any
ad shoot in this then please tell me in the comments below
and if you liked this video then please
like this video and
share it with your friends and if it is
on your channel then till now I have
uploaded five videos of IC38 Life Insurance Exam
so you can watch them also and
also subscribe to this channel ok
friends thank you
[Music]